不久之前 我们力挽狂澜
In hindsight, we accomplished what was required.
由于宇宙大帝的苏醒
With Unicron's awakening
我们不得不采取非常手段
extreme measures needed to be taken.
与宿敌并肩作战
Enemies became allies
向同伴托付重担
allies became confidants.
最终 借助领导模块的力量
And, with the Matrix of Leadership
地球得以平安无事
the planet Earth was saved.
但这却是以巨大的个人牺牲为代价…
Though at immeasurable personal cost...
在擎天柱失去领导模块的同时
When Optimus surrendered the Matrix
也失去了历代领袖所积累下来的智慧
he'd lost more than the collective wisdom of the Primes.
他们是谁？
Who are they?
是我们的死敌！
Our mortal enemies!
…他遗忘了自我
... He lost himself.
这解释不通啊
That doesn't follow.
擎天柱依旧认识威震天！
Optimus knew Megatron!
而且好得就跟老相识一样！
They were like BFFs!
如果说擎天柱不记得自己的名字
If Optimus did not know his own name
也许是因为他当时还没有被选为领袖
perhaps it is because the title of Prime hasn't yet been granted to him.
- 哈？\N- 什么？
- Huh?\N- What?
再说一遍？
Say again?
由于领导模块的力量不再护佑他
With the power of the Matrix no longer within him
理所当然的 他回到了成为领袖之前的状态：
it would stand to reason that Optimus has reverted to his pre-Prime state:
历史档案保管员 奥利安・派克斯
the historical archivist, Orion Pax.
你是说 他是这么认为的
You mean, in his mind.
你是说他现在是个图书管理员\N而且是个霸天虎？！
Are you telling me Prime thinks he is some kind of librarian and a Decepticon?!
全体船员注意
Attention, crew.
我们的贵客目前尚须独处
Our guest is currently in isolation
以适应新的环境
to help ease his transition.
当你们见到奥利安・派克斯时
But when Orion Pax emerges
必须以礼相待
he is to be shown every courtesy.
如果有人胆敢称呼他“擎天柱” 那我会揪出他的扬声器
And the first to address him as "Optimus Prime" will have his voice-box torn out.
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron.
无论如何 任由一个前任汽车人在这里晃荡
Is it wise, to allow an Autobot, current or former
这明智吗？
full run of the premises?
这艘船上的任何风吹草动都逃不过我的眼睛
Nothing happens aboard this ship without my knowledge.
你最好牢记这一点 毒蜘蛛
You will do well to remember that, Airachnid.
不过没什么好担心的
But there's no need for concern.
奥利安并不像擎天柱那般骁勇善战
Orion does not possess the same fight Optimus is so renown for.
那他对我们有何用？
Then what use is he to our Cause?
啊 放心吧 奥利安会证明自己的价值的
Ah, rest assured, Orion Pax will indeed earn his stripes.
欢迎回归胜利之师
Welcome back to the winning team.
是否成为霸天虎需要做出选择 福勒探员
Being a Decepticon is a choice, Agent Fowler.
我绝不相信擎天柱会在有生之年做出这样的决定
One that I have a hard time believing Optimus would make at any point in his life.
所以 如果他和虎子们狼狈为奸…
So, if he's riding with the 'Cons...
…肯定是威震天给他灌了某种迷魂汤
... it's because Megatron is working some kind of voodoo.
奥利安・派克斯也许现在不知道自己是汽车人
Orion Pax may not currently be an Autobot up here
但我坚信在他的内心深处 绝不会放弃追逐理想
but I must believe, he will never stop being one in here.
我们必须找到他来确认这点
We must locate him to know for certain.
等等 山姆大叔在我背上装了块芯片
Hold up. I have a chip lodged in my behind that let's Uncle Sam know
以防止我开小差
when I stop for donuts.
难道你们就没办法追踪到擎天柱了？
Are you telling me you can't just track Prime?
擎天柱的信号自他进入地心后就再也没出现过
Optimus's signal has not reappeared since he embarked for Earth's core.
但我们必须全力去找他
But we must get to work finding him.
如此一来 我们还是有机会启用应急方案的
If we have any hope of initiating his contingency plan.
…应急方案？
Contingency plan?
什么应急方案？
What "contingency"?
那只是个词吗?
Is that even a word?
是钥匙芯片！
The Key card!
好吧 它是做什么用的？
So, what's it do?
用来启动魔力神球
It grants access to Vector Sigma
历代领袖的智慧宝库
the repository of the wisdom of the Primes.
那是一种超级计算机么？
Is that some sort of supercomputer?
那么 我们只要把擎天柱的记忆重新下载一遍就行了？
So, we can just download Optimus's memories back into him?
太棒了！这个大球在哪儿？
Great! Which one is the big V?
这个？还是后面哪个？
Over here? Somewhere in back?
魔力神球可不光是一个“超级计算机”杰克
Vector Sigma is more than a "supercomputer", Jack.
它是一种神秘力量的古老源泉
It is an ancient source of mystical power.
在塞博特恩上
On Cybertron.
汽车人俘虏了你 并让你一直处在休眠状态 奥利安
You had been a captive of the Autobots and locked in stasis for quite some time, Orion.
在这期间 我们已经流亡到了另一个世界
Long enough for us to be in exodus on another world.
流亡？为什么？
Exodus? Why?
都怪大军阀救护车的鲁莽行径
Because the Warlord Ratchet's careless actions
导致了这一切
led to this.
啊…
Ahhh...
…塞博特恩！
... Cybertron!
杰克逊・达比！不许你到外星球去！
Jackson Darby! You will NOT be travelling to another planet.
那我去！
I'm in!
你也不能去 神子
You're not going either, Miko.
你们谁都不许去
Not when one of YOU can.
琼是对的
June's right.
为什么要派一个男孩去做一个汽车人的工作？
Why send a boy to do a bot's job?
因为只有领袖才能启动魔力神球
Because only a Prime can access Vector Sigma.
或者领袖钦点之人
Or one chosen by a Prime.
擎天柱把钥匙芯片交给了杰克
Optimus gave the Key card to Jack.
它已经匹配了他独有的生命特征
It is now imprinted with his unique biosignature.
那么你的意思是 杰克算是名誉领袖了？
So, you mean Jack's like some kinda honorary Prime?
直说吧 要想让擎天柱变回那个我们熟知的汽车人 只有杰克能做到
Let's just say, Jack is the only one who can return Optimus to the Autobot we knew.
但为什么擎天柱故意置一个人类于险境？\N还是一个孩子？
But why would Optimus willfully endanger a human? A child?
我不是孩子了 妈妈！
I'm not a child, Mom!
也许擎天柱相信杰克大有潜力可挖？
Maybe Optimus believes there's more to Jack than meets the eye.
说这些都毫无意义
All of which is moot.
如果到不了塞博特恩 钥匙芯片对我们毫无用处
The Key-card is useless to us without the means of reaching Cybertron
而现在我们却是一筹莫展
which we at present do not possess.
伙计 那个怎么样？
Dude. What about THAT?
神子 环陆桥只能勉强送他们到地球轨道 记得吗？
Miko, the Ground bridge barely got them into Earth orbit, remember?
是啊 但是救护车造了这个
Yeah, but Ratchet built it.
他就不能给这东西增强功率吗？
Can't he just turbo-charge the thing?
我不相信救护车会做出这么可怕的事情
I cannot believe Ratchet capable of such horrors.
是啊 难以想象 放任这个江湖郎中追求权力会是什么后果
Yes. And to think the Doctor of Doom's mad quest for power continues...
他的爪牙把我们驱逐至这个星球轨道上
his marauders pursued us to this planet's orbit.
我们认为这星球上的物种还没准备好接受我们
We feel its species are not ready to behold us.
但我们已下定决心保卫这个星球 以避免重蹈我们的覆辙
But we have resolved to protect this world from the same tragedy which was dealt to our own.
我有一个问题 威震天
One question, Megatron.
我们为什么被称作霸天虎？
Why are we called Decepticons?
不过是汽车人的恐慌伎俩而已
Another craven Autobot scare tactic.
用这个名字来妖魔化我们
The name was meant to demonize us.
相反 我们将它视为荣誉的象征
Instead, we wear it as a badge of honour.
若追求真理被视作霸权的话
For if speaking the truth is deception
那我们甘当此罪
then we are gladly guilty.
奥利安 别着急
Now please, Orion.
还有很多时间给你补课
There will be plenty of time for catching up.
你现在得休息
You must rest.
威震天！
Megatron!
我会竭尽全力阻止救护车那罄竹难书的侵略暴行
I will do my part to stop Ratchet's unspeakable crimes of aggression.
我以自己的火种起誓
This I vow. With all my Spark.
看来我们成功获取了奥利安火种的信任
It seems we have successfully achieved control of Orion's spark.
现在要让他的脑子为我所用了
Now, to put his mind to work.
你清理完数据核心了吗?
Have you sanitized the data-core?
很好 我们的新档案员可以随心所欲地浏览我们的文件了
Excellent. Our new archivist will require unlimited access to our files.
若让他不巧撞见敏感信息 恐怕会带来不良后果
It would be counterproductive for him to stumble upon any sensitive information.
两份“巨无霸汉堡”特色餐 请慢用！
Two "body slamburger" specials. Enjoy!
嘿 杰克！
Hey Jack!
赛拉！
Sierra!
怎么我最近一直没见到你？
How come I never see you around?
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
我们有化学反应的啊
We have chemistry together.
呃 化学课！我是指化学课
Ehm, "class"! Chemistry class.
我是说 课堂以外的时候
I mean, outside of school.
我从来没在聚会上或是商场里看过你
I never see you at any parties or the mall.
嗯 大部分时间我都带着帽子站在这里
Well, mostly I'm here, wearing the hat.
而且你也知道 准备变动指数考试得下相当的功夫
And you never can study too hard for the old SATs, you know.
而且 我还有些别的…事情
And, there's some other... stuff.
噢！先别走！
Oh. Don't go anywhere!
KO汽车快餐欢迎您 请问您要点…
Welcome to K.O. drive-in, may I take your...
五点了 杰克 你该下班了
5 PM, Jack. Your shift is over.
我们该走了
Let's go.
哦！原来是“这事”
Oh! That kind of... "stuff".
赛拉！等等！
Sierra, wait!
…她是我妈妈！
She's my mother!
你妈穿皮衣真有型
Your mom looks good in leather.
还骑在你的摩托上
On your bike.
我不是故意要毁了你的社交生活的
Didn't mean to decimate your social life.
又不是第一次了
Not the first time.
有擎天柱的消息了吗？
Any sign of Optimus?
暂时没有
Not today.
只是暂时的！
Not yet!
当我们在塞博特恩内战中取得优势之时 我们占领了铁堡的档案馆
When we stormed the Iacon Hall of Records in the winning days of the war for Cybertron
从那里得到了一些高度机密文件
we acquired highly classified files.
这些文件被汽车人加密过了 我们无法破译
Files written with Autobot codes, which we had been unable to decipher.
汽车人的密文 对铁堡档案员奥利安・派克斯而言那是手到擒来啊
Autobot codes, which the Iacon archivist Orion Pax should have no trouble cracking.
考虑到潜在的风险
Considering what's at stake
我们是不是该加强这附近的安保？
shouldn't we beef up the security around here?
击倒 我倒认为奥利安需要一个完全不受威胁或拘束的环境
Knockout, I believe that Orion will perform most effectively
才会有效地完成他的工作
if he does not feel threatened or confined in any way.
当然 奥利安的工作室靠近能量储藏室绝非偶然
However, it is no coincidence that Orion's work-station is located in direct proximity to the Energon storage vault.
因为能量储藏室随时有人监管…
Which is under constant surveillance...
…陛下英明
Well played.
救护车！你在增强环陆桥的功率吗？
Ratchet! Are you turbo-charging the Ground-bridge?
只是随便弄弄
Tinkering.
不必抱太大期望
No need to get anyone's hopes up, just yet.
奥利安！“铁堡”计划进展得如何了？
Orion! How fares project "Iacon"?
恐怕我的技艺生疏了
I am a bit rusty, I fear.
我只破译了三个条目
I've only managed to decode three entries.
都是些什么内容？
And what do these entries comprise?
这些都是我在休眠期间的档案
They were logged by Autobot archivist during the war after I entered stasis.
我唯一了解的信息是
My only knowledge of its content so far
它们是坐标
is that they are coordinates
目标地点正是这个星球
targeting locations on this very planet.
我猜测 这些地方可能藏有塞博特恩的飞船
I surmise that they could indicate hiding places for vessels
用于保管某些东西
shuttled from Cybertron for safe-keeping.
比如历史文件或者艺术品？
Such as historical documents or cultural artifacts?
我更担心他们藏匿了大规模杀伤性武器
My greatest fear would be weapons of mass destruction.
以便不时之需
Hidden away for later use.
那更说明我们得竭尽全力
All the more reason it is essential that we do everything in our power
阻止汽车人得到这些飞船
to keep said vessels from Autobot reach.
能有你相助是我们的造化 奥利安・派克斯
We are fortunate to have you on our side, Orion Pax.
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron.
有一个信息令我很困惑
I am puzzled by one particular finding.
很多历史资料中提及您的副官红蜘蛛
I have discovered several historic references to Starscream as your second-in-command.
但我却没在船上看到他
Yet I have not seen him aboard the ship.
很不幸 红蜘蛛指挥官已经牺牲了
Sadly, Commander Starscream is dead.
奥利安的问题太多了
Orion asks many questions.
对一个档案员来说这是好品质 但作为霸天虎则不然
A valuable trait in an archivist, but not in a Decepticon.
要不了多久 他就会识破我们的骗局
It is a matter of time before he unravels our fabrications
并重拾他与生俱来的是非观念…
and his innate sense of right and wrong rises to the surface...
我只希望奥利安能完成“铁堡”计划
I only hope that Orion will complete project "Iacon"
在我干净彻底地 销毁他之前
before I am forced to destroy him, once and for all.
救护车！
Ratchet!
你醒了吗？
You awake?
紧急情况！
This is an emergency!
福勒探员！是擎天柱吗？
Agent Fowler! Is it Optimus?
是虎子！
It's 'Cons!
他们又闯进了两个月前他们袭击过的军用实验室
And they're busting into the same military research lab they hit two months ago.
又想建太空桥了？
Another Space-bridge?
最重要的是擎天柱和他们在一起
But for all we know Optimus is riding with them.
出发！
Roll out!
放下动力装置！
Drop the power source!
你们是不是缺个人？
Aren't you missing someone?
把桥准备好！
Ready for that bridge!
我们一定代你们向柱子问好
We'll be sure to tell the big O you said "Hello".
阿尔茜！
Arcee!
见鬼
Scrap.
擎天柱在哪儿？
Where's Optimus?
回答我！
Answer me!
什么？！
What?!
阿尔茜…
Arcee...
让我来好好招待她
Allow me to welcome her aboard.
不！别说当着奥利安的面摧毁一个汽车人
No! If Orion so much as lays eyes on another Autobot
哪怕让他看到别的汽车人
let alone be allowed to witness its destruction
都会让他对之前相信的事情产生怀疑
everything he currently believes will be called into question.
立即确保阿尔茜被护送着离开这艘船！
See to it that Arcee is escorted off this ship immediately!
奥利安！请回到你的工作站
Orion! Please return to your station.
这是威震天陛下的命令
Lord Megatron's orders.
我听到了骚动声
I heard a commotion.
什么？
What the...?
你既没确定霸天虎的位置
You weren't able to determine the Decepticons' location
也不确定擎天柱是否在船上？
or if Optimus was even aboard ship?
我…不能确认
I... can't confirm.
隔板！
Bulkhead!
干嘛！？那个你有用吗？
What? You needed that?
我唯一需要的就是我们的头头回来！
Only thing I need is our head honcho back!
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
要是有人真心想救擎天柱 肯定会有办法
If any of us needed rescuing, Optimus would have found a way.
我没找到 就那么简单
I didn't. Simple as that.
救护车！
Ratchet!
你们都做了什么？
What happened out there?
我接到报告说十多人受伤了
Reports indicate at least a dozen wounded.
这让我怎么去解释
The hit's on me to provide some explanation.
你们干脆都回家去
You bots better get your act together or the Pentagon
要不五角大楼会让我封了你们的基地
will make me shut down your base.
那你们能去哪儿？
But... where would you go?
谁知道 也许他们会把我们用船运到某个岛上
Who knows. Maybe they'll ship us out to some island
或者是把我们送上太空！
or fire us into space!
我们倒乐得轻松
Wouldn't that be a welcome relief.
我不怪福勒！
I don't blame Fowler!
要是擎天柱在 他会在与虎子交战之前
Optimus would have evacuated all humans in the area
疏散那片区域的所有人类
before engaging the 'Cons.
实际上我们才不知道擎天柱会怎么做 因为他根本就不在这！
We don't actually know what Optimus would have done because he's not here!
你真会说废话 小隔
You're pretty good at stating the obvious, Bulk.
能讲点我们不知道的吗？
Anything else you'd like to mention that we already know?
在孩子们面前我没什么可说的
Nothing I can say in front of the children.
嘿！我们就不能看看积极的一面吗？
Hey! Aren't we overlooking one positive?
没人注意到虎子们接下来要做什么吗？
Nobody's talking about what the 'Cons just got their claws on.
是啊 他们终于如愿以偿
Yes, we managed to allow them to finally
得到了太空桥的动力装置！
acquire a power source for their space bridge!
那怎么能算积极的方面？
And how exactly that would be a positive?
我们让他们造好太空桥
We let them finish building their Space-bridge.
为什么？好让他们把更多的僵尸\N从塞博特恩带到这里来吗？
Why? So they can bring more zombies back from Cybertron?
不 好让我们去接管它
No. So we can commandeer it.
用它把我送到塞博特恩去
And use it to send me to Cybertron.
哇哦 那真是个好主意
Woah. That's a pretty good idea.
噢 好吧
Oh well.
如果神子觉得那是个好主意…
If Miko thinks it's a good idea...
没人把它当成儿戏 但你们以前曾经夺取过太空桥！
Nobody saying it will be easy but you've seized the Space-bridge before!
我们只是炸飞了一个
We blew one up.
那跟夺取并控制一个是两码事
That's a whole lot different than seizing and holding one.
小蜂是对的 我们先得找到那玩意
Bee's right. We have to find that thing first.
我说！
Hellooo!
要是太空桥的话 难道不应该在…？
If it's a space bridge... isn't it?
“太空”指的是传送范围
The term "space" refers to its transport range
不是它本身的地理位置
not its physical location.
上次事件以后我们就一直在监控地球轨道
And we've been monitoring Earth's orbit since the last one
要是有太空桥的话我们会知道的
we'd know if it were there.
那么太空桥可能就在地球上的某处？
So, the Bridge could be somewhere right here on Earth?
这相当于在一个废车场里找一个涡轮机
Like trying to find a servo at a scrapyard.
那我们最好现在就行动
Then maybe we better start looking.
但现状没有改变：
But the fact remains:
我们不知道霸天虎要对擎天柱做什么
We don't know what the Decepticons have in store for Optimus.
也不知道他是否还健在
Or if he's truly safe from harm.
红蜘蛛！
Starscream!
是“红蜘蛛指挥官”
That's "Commander Starscream".
你们短路了吗？
What's your malfunction?
立刻放下武器
Lower those weapons immediately.
对不起 长官 但是威震天陛下有令 如果你回到船上
I'm sorry, Sir, but Lord Megatron ordered that you be taken into custody
就立即将你逮捕
should you ever return to the ship.
什么？
What?
显然 这中间有些差错
Clearly, there has been a mistake.
看呐！
Lo!
擎天柱？！
Optimus Prime?!